<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Jonathan Satria's blog</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2016-01-20T14:11:22+00:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Jonathan Satria</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>jonathan.bytes@gmail.com</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lisbon, Portugal]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/Lisbon-Portugal/" />
  <id>/Lisbon-Portugal</id>
  <updated>2015-12-23T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Satria</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan.bytes@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lisboa&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-lisboa&quot;&gt;Lisboa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#orientation-of-lisbon&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-orientation-of-lisbon&quot;&gt;Orientation of Lisbon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#travelling-to-lisbon&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-travelling-to-lisbon&quot;&gt;Travelling to Lisbon&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#when-to-go&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-when-to-go&quot;&gt;When to go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#how-to-get-there&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-how-to-get-there&quot;&gt;How to get there&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#where-to-stay&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-where-to-stay&quot;&gt;Where to stay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#public-transportation&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-public-transportation&quot;&gt;Public Transportation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#itinerary&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-itinerary&quot;&gt;Itinerary&lt;/a&gt;    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#day-1-arrive&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-day-1-arrive&quot;&gt;Day 1: Arrive&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#day-2-belem&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-day-2-belem&quot;&gt;Day 2: Belem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#day-3-sintra&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-day-3-sintra&quot;&gt;Day 3: Sintra&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#travel-tips&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-travel-tips&quot;&gt;Travel Tips!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lisboa&quot;&gt;Lisboa&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been almost a month since my first post and a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; has happened already! The spring semester started at Georgia Tech OMSCS, I started my side project with the Play! Framework and Java, 
and most recently returned from a weekend trip to Lisbon, Portugal. It was a fantastic first trip to Europe after moving to England (I’ve been to Europe many times before) and as such, I decided
to stray away from my planned tech talk and write about the trip. My goal is to share some itinerary and travel tips for Lisbon in hopes that they might be useful for others thinking about visiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having been to many great cities in Europe, Lisbon did not disappoint. The sites were fantastic, the weather was perfect (considering English weather at this time), food was inexpensive, and the
Portuguese were friendly and inviting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;orientation-of-lisbon&quot;&gt;Orientation of Lisbon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisbon is a vibrant, bustling, and culturally engaging capital city that has a rich history due to its locational. As one of the most ancient cities in Europe, 
Lisbon changed many hands between empires, some of which were the Romans, Moors, and the Spanish empires. Portugal was also the first global empire during the Age of Discovery, promoting its wealth, power, and status.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On All Saint’s Day in 1755, Lisbon experienced an earthquake that registered 9.2 according to the now used Richter scale – greater than the 2011 Japan earthquake. Much of the city was destroyed due to the
 earthquake itself and the fires, which started because of the abundant candles being used to observe the religious occasion. The destruction caused by the earthquake marked a decline in Portugal’s wealth and power, however, 
 the city itself cleared and rebuilt in a staggering amount of time. Today, the effects of the earthquake can be seen in the distinguishable differences in the layout and design of Lisbon between different neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travelling-to-lisbon&quot;&gt;Travelling to Lisbon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;when-to-go&quot;&gt;When to go&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travelling in &lt;strong&gt;January&lt;/strong&gt; meant it was low-season in Lisbon, which meant there were few crowds and rarely any lines. This also meant that the many beautiful sights of Lisbon were easily photographed sans-people.
The weather was mostly bright and sunny, with temperatures around 50-60F.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
     &lt;a href=&quot;/images/thumb_lisbon1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumb_lisbon1.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-to-get-there&quot;&gt;How to get there&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are quick and inexpensive flights to Lisbon from Stansted (most of my travel will be from London area airports) served by most budget airlines. The flight itself is around 2.5 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;where-to-stay&quot;&gt;Where to stay&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of affordable and fantastic flats offered on AirBnB. The challenge is finding the right neighborhood to stay in. I stayed in a hostel in Alfama which is on the eastern side of the city. 
The advantage of staying in Alfama is that it seemed particularly less touristy than Baixa (closer to the city “center”). Tram 28 and 12 were a short walk away and allowed quick travel into the Praca Figuera 
and Martin Monez. As the only neighborhood that wasn’t destroyed by the earthquake, Alfama’s charm also benefits from it’s original medieval street layout, look, and feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;public-transportation&quot;&gt;Public Transportation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lisbon is a walkable city, but in order to see each of the neighborhoods, Lisbon’s public transportation is helpful and inexpensive. However, I found it a bit of a nuisance that most maps only printed either the 
Metro &lt;strong&gt;or&lt;/strong&gt; Tram lines – not both. Nonetheless, the tram provided the easiest form of transportation, in particular the historic 28E and 12 trams. Do be mindful of pick-pocketers while enjoying the views from the tram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
     &lt;a href=&quot;/images/thumb_tram28.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumb_tram28.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;itinerary&quot;&gt;Itinerary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-1-arrive&quot;&gt;Day 1: Arrive&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a morning &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.insidelisbon.com/package/best-of-lisbon-walk/&quot;&gt;walking tour&lt;/a&gt; to get an overview of the city and its neighborhoods.
    &lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
       &lt;a href=&quot;/images/thumb_lisbon2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumb_lisbon2.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy lunch in Baixa and explore the neighborhood for its shopping.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/Attraction_Review-g189158-d2320746-Reviews-A_Ginjinha-Lisbon_Lisbon_District_Central_Portugal.html&quot;&gt;A Ginjinha&lt;/a&gt; for some delicious but dangerously potent cherry liquor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have dinner at a restaurant offering &lt;em&gt;fado&lt;/em&gt; in Bairro Alto
    &lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
           &lt;a href=&quot;/images/thumb_fado.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumb_fado.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-2-belem&quot;&gt;Day 2: Belem&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the 15 train to Belem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try traditional &lt;em&gt;Pasteis&lt;/em&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://pasteisdebelem.pt/&quot;&gt;Pasteis de Belem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit the Monastarios de Jeronimos and Tower of Belem. Buy a combined ticket of €18 to save on individual tickets
    &lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;/images/thumb_monastarios.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumb_monastarios.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

    &lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
           &lt;a href=&quot;/images/thumb_tower.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumb_tower.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try a traditional sandwich at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/Restaurant_Review-g189158-d2324445-Reviews-Pao_Pao_Queijo_Queijo-Lisbon_Lisbon_District_Central_Portugal.html&quot;&gt;Pio Pio Quiejo Quiejo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make your way back to Lisbon, go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://castelodesaojorge.pt/&quot;&gt;Castelo de Sao Jorge&lt;/a&gt; to enjoy the castle and watch the most spectacular sunset. Grab a glass of wine if you can!
    &lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
       &lt;a href=&quot;/images/thumb_lisbon3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumb_lisbon3.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
   &lt;/figure&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoy dinner in the Alfama. There are plenty of options many offering variations of the same thing. Make sure to enjoy some Tinto with dinner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;day-3-sintra&quot;&gt;Day 3: Sintra&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the regional train to Sintra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit the ruins of the old Moorish castle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
         &lt;a href=&quot;/images/thumb_moorish_castle.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumb_moorish_castle.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parquesdesintra.pt/en/parks-and-monuments/park-and-national-palace-of-pena/&quot;&gt;Pena Castle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
         &lt;a href=&quot;/images/thumb_pena_palace.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thumb_pena_palace.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Train back to Lisbon and enjoy dinner in a tapas restaurant in the Alfama district&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel-tips&quot;&gt;Travel Tips!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This applies to any travel where a cellular data connection isn’t available: download an offline Google Map of the city. GPS still works and having a live map is incredibly helpful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The LisboaCard may be helpful for travellers interested in visiting a lot of museums. Do some research to see which museum’s you’d actually like to go to. In my case it was more economical
to travel using the VivaViagem card with the 24-hour pass on days that I stayed entirely in Lisbon, and the “Zapping” method for single rides.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At sit down restaurants it is customary for preappetizers to be brought out, like bread would be brought out in the States. However, this food isn’t free or complimentary. You can kindly
tell the waiter/waitress that you simply don’t want it, or push it to the side and it will be collected later.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wear comfortable walking shoes. The cobblestone streets absolutely necessitate the need for proper footwear.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rick Steve’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Rick-Steves-Snapshot-Lisbon/dp/1598805886&quot;&gt;snapshot guidebook&lt;/a&gt; is a great resource to read before and during the trip. Having it also gives you a €5 discount on the Inside Lisbon walking tour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Lisbon-Portugal/&quot;&gt;Lisbon, Portugal&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Satria at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Jonathan Satria's blog&lt;/a&gt; on January 19, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/first-post/" />
  <id>/first-post</id>
  <updated>2015-12-23T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2015-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Jonathan Satria</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>jonathan.bytes@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class=&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul id=&quot;markdown-toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#welcome&quot; id=&quot;markdown-toc-welcome&quot;&gt;Welcome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;!-- /#table-of-contents --&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;welcome&quot;&gt;Welcome&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my &lt;strong&gt;second&lt;/strong&gt; blog. I learned a very important lesson yesterday and that is to never relent on backing up your disk. Whether it’s for your graduate coursework, latest feature work, or what you assume is an insignificant WordPress blog – back it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summer 2014 I set up a WordPress blog that was hosted on my DigitalOcean VPS. It was a personal exercise to learn how to set up a server with my own domain and install WordPress from scratch. I hadn’t done such a thing before and I was pleased when I completed the task. I posted a bit, tinkered with SSL and security… I even had a dog-watch surveillance web app running with my RaspberryPi! Things were going well. But then work and life took over and the blogging and tinkering slowed and ceased altogether around April of this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I decided revive my small project and issued myself a new challenge: set up nginx as a reverse proxy so that I could have both the Apache server running WordPress and a web application running on the same server on the same domain name. Given the relatively simple architecture, I thought the task would be just that – simple and straightforward. Unfortunately, it was anything but and I quickly dug myself into an irreversible hole. It wasn’t so much the nginx or server setup that did it, but at some point when I tried to revert to a previous snapshot I had taken, the disk became corrupted. I’m still investigating what may have happened, but needless to say, I learned my lesson. &lt;em&gt;backup!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I’ve got this new blog running on Jekyll and hosted on GitHub pages. I hadn’t heard of Jekyll until the aforementioned crisis and  discovered it on my search for a funky-fresh new way to blog, with something less behemoth than WordPress. I’ve been liking it so far, especially because there’s a lot more under the hood that I get to poke at and play with. The tech stack is also new and interesting to me, so it’ll be a good learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading to the end of this blog post! I’m determined to post more (in addition to backing up) to this blog, especially since so much has happened with life in the last 3 months with moving to Cambridge. Hopefully these posts will be of interest to others, whether it be in travel, tech, or just good life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tldr&lt;/em&gt;: Hosed my first blog and learned that I should always backup. This is my new blog and I’m glad you’re interested in reading it!&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/first-post/&quot;&gt;First Post&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Jonathan Satria at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Jonathan Satria's blog&lt;/a&gt; on December 23, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
